<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam Castonguay on Adam Castonguay</title>
    <link>https://accastonguay.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adam Castonguay on Adam Castonguay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Adam Castonguay 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping country of origin with Leaflet and Shiny</title>
      <link>https://accastonguay.github.io/post/origin-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://accastonguay.github.io/post/origin-mapping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a few weeks, I will be moving to Brisbane for work. One thing of Melbourne that I enjoyed was its multicultural feel and the diversity of restaurants that come with it.
I was therefore curious to find out whether Brisbane is as multicultural as Melbourne and decided to map the country of origin of residents in Brisbane by country of origin.
This is obviously not new; there are some nice maps doing the same, e.g., &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sbs.com.au/news/map/where-australias-immigrants-were-born-brisbane&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
However, itt always feels better to do it by ourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data, at the scale of the Statistical Sreas level 2 (SA2), comes from the latest census (2016) completed by the Australian bureau of Statistics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&#34;overflow:hidden&#34; scrolling=&#34;yes&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=600&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;https://accastonguay.shinyapps.io/brisbane_ethinicity/&#34;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated modelling of stormwater treatment systems uptake</title>
      <link>https://accastonguay.github.io/publication/nbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://accastonguay.github.io/publication/nbs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling urban water management transitions: a case of rainwater harvesting</title>
      <link>https://accastonguay.github.io/publication/rwht_uptake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://accastonguay.github.io/publication/rwht_uptake/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards water sensitive cities in Asia: an interdisciplinary journey</title>
      <link>https://accastonguay.github.io/publication/wsc-asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://accastonguay.github.io/publication/wsc-asia/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://accastonguay.github.io/cv/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://accastonguay.github.io/cv/cv/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
2015-Present
:    Ph.D. Candidate in Civil Engineering, Monash University, Melbourne, Australia   
     Thesis title: Modelling the adoption of nature-based solutions for stormwater management:
An agent-based approach   
     Supervisors: Prof. Ana Deletic, Dr. Christian Urich and Dr. Md Sayed Iftekhar  

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
2011-2014
:    M.Sc. Environmental Management, CAU University of Kiel, Kiel, Germany
     &lt;br /&gt;
     Thesis title: Assessment of resilience and adaptability
of social-ecological systems - a case study of the
Banaue rice terraces.   
     Supervisors: Prof. Felix Muller and PD Benjamin Burkhard  


&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
2004-07
:    B.A. International Relations, University Laval, Quebec,
     Canada
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;contract-employment&#34;&gt;Contract employment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;2015-2016&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;em&gt;Research Officer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Collaborative Research Center for Water Sensitive Cities,
Clayton, Australia.&lt;br /&gt;
Provide a diagnostic and best practice knowledge to guide investment programs linked with the Asian
Development Bank operations and private sector partners in developing cities of the Asia-Pacific region. Apply the Water Sensitive Cities Index in Mandalay (Myanmar) and Suva (Fiji).&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;2013&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intern&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Convention on Biological Diversity, Montreal, Canada&lt;br /&gt;
Internship on the contribution to the GBO-4.
The information gathered in the literature review
was summarized and published in the GBO-4 in 2014.
Review literature on Aichi Targets 6 (fisheries) and
9 (invasive alien species).&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;2013&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;em&gt;Collaborative research fellow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
German Society for International Cooperation (GIZ),
Los Banos, Philippines.&lt;br /&gt;
Research stay for master&amp;rsquo;s thesis at the Crop and
Environmental Science Division of the International
Rice Research Institute (IRRI). The research was part of
the LEGATO Project and was funded by the Advisory
Service on Agricultural Research for Development
(BEAF) of GIZ.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;publications&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt; Peer-reviewed article &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
2018
:    **Castonguay, A.C.**, Urich, C., Iftekhar, M.S., Deletic, A. 2018. Modelling urban water management transitions: A case of rainwater harvesting. Environmental Modelling &amp; Software 105, [DOI: 10.1016/j.envsoft.2018.05.001](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S136481521630994X)
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
2017
:    Barron, N.J., Kuller, M., Yasmin, T., **Castonguay, A.C.**, Copa, V., Duncan-Horner, E., Gimelli, F.M., Jamali, B., Nielsen, J.S., Ng, K., Novalia, W., Shen, P.F., Conn, R.J., Brown, R.R., Deletic, A. 2017. Towards water sensitive cities in Asia: an interdisciplinary journey. Water Science &amp; Technology 77(9), [DOI: 10.2166/wst.2017.287](http://wst.iwaponline.com/content/early/2017/05/19/wst.2017.287)
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
2016
:    **Castonguay, A.C.**, Burkhard, B., Muller, F., Horgan, F., Settele, J. 2016. Resilience and adaptability of rice terrace social-ecological systems: a case study of a local community&#39;s perception in Banaue, Philippines. Ecology and Society 21(2):15. [http://dx.doi.org/10.5751/ES-08348-210215](http://dx.doi.org/10.5751/ES-08348-210215) [(PDF)](papers/Castonguay_et_al_2016.pdf) 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt; Conference proceeding &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
2016
:   **Castonguay, A.C.**, Urich, C., Iftekhar, M.S., Deletic, A. 2016. Modelling urban transition: a case of rainwater harvesting. In: Sauvage, S., Sanchez-Perez, J.M., Rizzoli, A.E. (Eds.), 2016. Proceedings of the 8th International Congress on Environmental Modelling and Software, July 10-14, Toulouse, France. (ISBN: 978-8890357459)[(PDF)](http://scholarsarchive.byu.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1568&amp;context=iemssconference) 
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 

&lt;h1 id=&#34;awards-and-scholarships&#34;&gt;Awards and scholarships&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;2015&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Monash Residential Services Postgraduate Merit Scholarship, Monash University&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;2015 &amp;ndash; 2018&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Faculty of Engineering International Postgraduate Research Scholarship (FEIPRS), Monash University&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;2013&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis grant, Advisory Service on Agricultural Research for Development (BEAF) of the German Society for International Cooperation (GIZ)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;selected-courses-and-training&#34;&gt;Selected courses and training&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;2012&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;em&gt;Erasmus Intensive Programme&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Adam Mickiewicz University, Poznan, Poland.&lt;br /&gt;
Ecological state of the lake during restoration
measures&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;2009&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;em&gt;Summer exchange program&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Pontificia Universidad Catolica del Peru, Lima, Peru.&lt;br /&gt;
Introduction to business administration in Latin America&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;2008&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Summer exchange program&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Nankai University, Tianjin, China&lt;br /&gt;
    Chinese language and culture course
&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;reviews&#34;&gt;Reviews&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Land (MDPI)
&amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resilience and adaptability of rice terrace social-ecological systems: a case study of a local community&#39;s perception in Banaue, Philippines</title>
      <link>https://accastonguay.github.io/publication/resilience-banaue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://accastonguay.github.io/publication/resilience-banaue/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling the uptake of stormwater treatment systems</title>
      <link>https://accastonguay.github.io/project/abm-stormwater/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://accastonguay.github.io/project/abm-stormwater/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Cities are increasingly exposed to extreme climate events such as floods and droughts. Land use change is also expected to reduce the availability of green spaces and intensify extreme heat events. Given these pressures on the quality of life of urban dwellers, there is a great need to improve the integrated management of water to enable sustainable development of rapidly growing cities and improve human well-being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A promising way to make urban communities more liveable is to invest in green water technologies, that is, decentralised and low-energy water supply, wastewater and stormwater solutions, to foster the transition to more sustainable and resilient cities. However, the adoption of multifunctional water technologies is a complex issue that requires cross-disciplinary approaches, demanding innovative thinking and practice. Despite the increasing body of literature on the services and benefits of decentralised water technologies, several barriers and uncertainties (technical, economic, social) to their adoption remain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to develop an agent-based model to be used as a tool to explore different strategies and policy mechanisms to enable the uptake of nature-based solution for stormwater treatment and harvesting, such as rainwater tanks, raingardens and constructed wetlands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More specifically, the model should be able to simulate the behavior and decision-making of the most important actors in cities (water utility, local councils, housegholds, etc.). It should also be able to replicate the interactions to reproduce the influence that actors can have on other actors&amp;rsquo; decision-making. Finally, the the model should allow for dynamic simulations to test and explore the development of the urban stormater management system over time and under scenarios of population growth and climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rainwater-tank-npv-calculator&#34;&gt;Rainwater tank NPV calculator&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the outputs of the model is the assessment of the value of rainwater tanks, based on multiple costs and water saving benefit. Below is a R Shiny app to caluculate the Net Present Value of three volumes of tanks (2, 5 and 10 kl) and two usages (outdoor use only and combined indoor-outdoor use). You can enter your household characteristics (e.g., household size, roof area, garden area, etc.) and rainwater tank-related costs and other data (e.g., installation costs, maintenance costs, expected lifespan, etc.) to see how many years are needed for the investment to become profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&#34;overflow:hidden&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; width=&#34;1000&#34; height=&#34;1000&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;https://accastonguay.shinyapps.io/rwht_app/&#34;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resilience of rice terraces social-ecological systems</title>
      <link>https://accastonguay.github.io/project/resilience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://accastonguay.github.io/project/resilience/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
